Guide to the New Haven Peace Coalition collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
New Haven Peace Coalition collection
1982-2005
MS 2016
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.75
(2 boxes)
This collection is comprised of peace rally handouts, newsclippings, related third party materials, and correspondence of the New Haven Peace Coalition, a local grass-roots effort, begun to protest the Gulf War, 1990-1991, and later the Second Gulf War and related conflicts. Also included are materials related to the Connecticut Peace Coalition, a broader effort of the New Haven Peace Coalition, and the national Iraq Pledge of Resistance, 2003.
New Haven Peace Coalition
Scope and Contents
This collection is comprised of peace rally handouts, newsclippings, related third party materials, and correspondence of the New Haven Peace Coalition, a local grass-roots effort, begun to protest the Gulf War, 1990-1991, and later the Second Gulf War and related conflicts. Also included are materials related to the Connecticut Peace Coalition, a broader effort of the New Haven Peace Coalition, and the national Iraq Pledge of Resistance, 2003.
Custodial History
Gift of Ms. Marjorie Van Cleef, 2015
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The material is arranged by accession and therein by type of material.
Iraq War, 2003-2011; Persian Gulf War, 1991; New Haven Peace Coalition; Women's International League for Peace and Freedom
- Inventory, 1990-2014
  - Leaflets, 1992-2014 (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
  - New Iraq Pledge of Resistance, 1991-2003 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Peace and Justice News & Views, 1996-2004 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1990-2003 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Clippings and News Articles, 1990-2004 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Additional material, 1982-2004; Accession 2016-M-006
  - Leaflets, 1984-2004 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Articles and news clippings, 1982-2004 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Faslania", 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1983, 2000-2004 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Ground Zero, 1999-2003 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photograph and negatives, 1991, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 7)